If you could work from any location in the world, where would you go?
如果你可以在世界上任何地方工作，你会去哪里？
Picture filling in a spreadsheet on a sandy Caribbean island, or maybe a little rooftop cafe in Rome where you can sip an espresso while editing a social media video.
想象一下在加勒比海的小岛上填写电子数据表，或者在罗马的某个屋顶咖啡馆里，一边啜饮浓缩咖啡一边编辑社交媒体视频。
More and more countries are offering digital nomad visas and therefore the chance to work remotely, from wherever you'd like to.
越来越多的国家正在提供数字游民签证，从而提供了在任何你喜欢的地方远程工作的机会。
This way of working is on the rise.
这种工作方式正在兴起。
A 2023 report found that 11% of US workers now consider themselves a digital nomad, and this type of worker is expected to increase in number by more than 20 million in the next five years.
2023年的一份报告发现，11%的美国工作者现在认为自己是数字游民，预计未来五年内这类工作者的数量将增加超过2000万。
Traditionally, digital nomads have worked freelance.
传统上，数字游民从事自由职业。
They might be social media managers, software developers or copywriters, but now even traditional professions like accountants and lawyers are taking the leap.
他们可能是社交媒体经理、软件开发人员或文案撰稿人，但现在甚至连会计师和律师等传统职业也在跃跃欲试。
But what is the life of a digital nomad really like?
但数字游民的生活到底是什么样的呢？
Rowena Hennigan, who writes for Harvard Business Review, is a digital nomad along with her family.
为《哈佛商业评论》撰稿的罗威娜·亨尼根和她的家人都是数字游民。
They have a 'home base' in Spain but frequently go away for workcations that can last from weeks to months.
他们在西班牙有一个"大本营"，但经常去度假工作，时间从几周到几个月不等。
She says that compared to a 'traditional' model of raising children, "remote working has allowed my family to move away from that kind of intensity, and this way, we all get to move at a more sustainable and healthy pace."
她说，与"传统"的育儿模式相比，"远程工作让我的家人摆脱了那种压力，这样我们都能以更可持续、更健康的方式生活。"
Plus, her family are regularly exposed to new cultures, languages and natural beauty.
此外，她的家人经常接触新的文化、语言和自然美景。
Though it doesn't work for everyone.
不过，这并不适合所有人。
Francesca Specter, a writer for The Guardian, decided to country-hop where her 'office' included beaches, cafes and coworking spaces.
《卫报》的作家弗朗西斯卡·斯佩克特决定在不同国家间穿梭，她的"办公室"包括海滩、咖啡馆和共享办公空间。
But along with struggling to find reliable wi-fi and fighting bouts of loneliness, she wrote that she felt envious as she cooled her overheating laptop in the shade while holidaymakers relaxed by the pool.
但除了难以找到可靠的无线网络和应对孤独感的困扰外，她写道，当她在阴凉处给过热的笔记本电脑降温时，看到度假者们在泳池边放松，她感到嫉妒。
She said, "I was chronically firefighting unglamorous concerns such as missing luggage or sleep deprivation after an overnight flight delay."
她说："我长期疲于应对那些无聊乏味的问题，比如行李丢失，或者因航班延误过夜而睡眠不足。"
So, it's not for everyone, but if you ever feel like escaping the rat-race, why not give it a go?
所以，这并不适合所有人，但如果你曾想逃离激烈的竞争，为什么不试一试呢？